i'm canadian i
i flew from uh from canada uh yesterday
i flew uh flew down
um and uh i was gonna say flew up but
that doesn't make sense uh here's what
happened i'm going through security all
i forgot to do airport security all i
forgot to do is stick my chapstick in a
little ziploc bag where you put your
gels in your liquids
just forgot to stick it in there and
security guard decided to make an issue
with it right so it's actually a gel
you're supposed to put in the bag you
didn't put in the bag
i was like oh almost just forgotten i'll
i'll take it now he's like no no i need
to confiscate it now because you didn't
put it in the bag
i was like dude it's chapstick you know
what are you gonna do with chapstick you
know take me somewhere
granted it did say lip balm on it lip
balm
it's a lip balm joke that's uh
the most stressful thing i do i find
about coming coming down to
to work in the states here is the border
the board because the border
crossing into your kind it used to be
fun times used to be happy fun time
used to cross the border in the good old
days the americans are oh come come on
into our country we love those canadians
come on in here we love our neighbors to
the north get on in here this is
fantastic
come on in is that fruit is that an
apple is that an apple
put it down right remember when fruit
was the biggest security risk between
our nations
marylander like i don't care about the
narcotics is that kiwi down there hand
it over
let's send a boy it's kiwi i don't know
why i picked kiwi i thought it'd be
least defensive
there's some guys from new zealand in
the back
sorry but it's changed now they're
they're uh have you crossed the border
lately
going both ways canada or going into the
u.s or going into
it's they're mad all the time now
they're always mad
i tried to lighten it up last time went
through the guys like so you're uh
you're a comedian
i was like yeah that's right so uh so
what are you gonna be talking about
i was like i don't know depends on where
this goes
don't say that don't
don't do this either it looks like a gun
apparently what's going on
this is a a true story i was well it's
all true this is just more true
there's just more i was crossing the
borders a couple years ago now i got to
the border i had the guy my passport
he took it he scanned it through the
machine first thing he said after he
scanned through the machine
don't make any sudden movements right so
i was like
okay and then he's like shut up her
vehicle give me the keys too
so i was like all right so i shut off
the vehicle i ham the key slowly right
because he said no sudden movements you
know here come the keys
i don't know i'm crouching down so much
right now take the front seat out of the
car in canada
we like to get a good quad workout while
we're driving
saves hours of gym time
but then he said to me in a couple of
moments i'm going to ask you to get out
of the car
and when you do if you make any sudden
movements at all we're going to take you
to the ground
that's what he said verbatim those and
the reason he said a couple moments
dukes any time for his armed buddies
to come out and surround the car i'm not
gonna make up the number for the store
either by the time i got out there was
there six of them surrounding the car
they never guns drawn be their hands on
their guns you know on their hips and
ready to
ready to shoot at canadian mode you know
waiting to bag me a canuck all week here
we go
i don't think he's doing this i think i
just added that i don't know why i added
that
should i shoot him i should have a
pirouette what are we doing you guys
this is the worst fear whatever
i was too great so so he opens a car
door um i step out
uh of course now now i'm i'm i'm
towering over this guy
right i'm way taller so now i'm afraid
he's gonna have like small man complex
or something
you know take the big guy down a peg or
two
right so i'm like everything's gonna be
okay everybody just calm down just take
it easy
i won't hurt you
now what did you want to say
i made that part up that's not true i
didn't put him on my shoulder he was
a little bigger than that but i was
freaked out i was scared i just went to
the back of the car
actually shoved me down on the hood in
the back like my face was squished
on the hood in the back of the car right
well it's the hood's not in the back of
the car
i drive a porsche so
comedy has been good to me
it's funnier and you realize uh
so they got me pinned down they
handcuffed me behind my back they
grabbed me with the armed guard and they
take me into the customs office i got
some kind of wanted fugitive or
something right
now i'm starting to get a little freaked
out right it doesn't seem like a like a
routine stop
anymore right imagine the people behind
me right bring a little freaked out
themselves right they see this car pull
up people jump out with guns
and they'll scare themselves you know
it's like eat the fruit lois eat the
fruit
[Laughter]
this banana that's almost a banana
because you need your potassium for jail
i got a show a couple weeks ago some
burly guy stood up in the back and he's
like that's true
[Applause]
so they're taking me into the customs
office and again absolutely true story i
was in there for like
i don't know like maybe five seconds
like not long at all and some guard
walks all nonchalantly from behind the
counter he's like oh
i guess this is a computer malfunction
you can just let him go
and that was it there's no explanation
no apology no place to go change nothing
where some of that fruit goes so you're
pretty fast am i right
i'll take it back across to canada where
it belongs
when i was crouching down like my my
quads actually started to
cramp up on me i'm not in great shape
that's uh i've noticed that lately so
i've been trying to do something about
it
uh last year i uh i started p90x have
you guys
have you heard of p90 he's laughing
already he's like you did not i finished
it
well i didn't quite finish it i didn't
want to get too big
um gotta keep my showbiz bud
you're right up front by the way so when
you go i hear that
um it's really close in fact
it's like you're yelling it in my ear
that's what it felt like
mentally just you know
um i did i started p90x anybody tried it
by applause who's tried p90x
applause who's yeah a lot of you wow
who's finished it beginning to end p90x
who's finished it by applause
wow we got like four or five people give
them a round of applause everybody
yeah well
i'll tell you why it's incredibly hard
to have four or five courageous people
coming to a room full of strangers
and feel the courage to lie to everybody
deserve an applause for that now it is
hard though it's crazy it's
it's so here's my experience with it i
put the first one see it's a lot of
stuff you can do at home push-ups pull
up stuff like that right so it's easy
you can do it at home
uh but the first one is it's chest and
back uh
and it starts out with push-ups do as
many push-ups as you can in a minute
okay so i i did my number and we don't
have a lot of time so let's just skip
the specifics
um it's just a number it doesn't matter
but right after that was done it was
pull-ups do as many pull-ups as you can
in a minute
uh pull up pull-ups it doesn't have to
be plural
i called in found out um
but soon as that was done it was back
was a different kind of push-up now it
was like a is like a military one
but do as many push as you can in a
minute again and it just went back and
forth
for an hour straight and if this isn't
just do a certain number
and then stop it's going to fatigue till
you're like i can't do any more oh so
you're done yeah oh that's about time
then
to start it again it was
back like an hour and i'll be honest
with you i'm gonna be honest with you
okay
about 10 minutes in um i was done
i could get no more push-ups i was on my
knees doing girl push-ups just come on
one more
um that's i guess why they're still so
that's why they're called girl push-ups
because they're incredibly difficult
to do i'll take it
um but then buddies count and two makes
it worse right 13 and 14 and i'm like
one
and then he's like set goals for
yourself and try to reach those goals
one i want to do the upper half
bottom half's easy gravity helps out
right
you got a half in i'm just going to stop
there
oh i was in so much pain that first week
of doing it i was in like i could barely
move my i'm not even exaggerating i
could barely move my arms that week it
was i was since
my kids were making fun of me because we
were eating and every spoonful of soup
felt like i was doing a rep
you know
okay i'm just gonna take a little
mid-set break and lick from the bowl
mid-set lick break i just realized i'm
eating
soup on the floor that's how we eat in
canada
you don't know when a grizzly bear is
going to attack
that's not true i made that up that's
not true
oh i was here's the funny thing though
when you do get that sore um it kind of
tricks your mind into thinking that
you're huge
because you could feel it everywhere
like i was walking around i was like
this stuff is working like i'm getting
jacked there's a picture i had during
that time
and i was standing there nobody around
me nothing around me at all and for
whatever reason my arm was like way out
here
right see my mind was like we're this
big now
we've got massive arms are you sure i'm
not right around here no trust me i'm
your mind
we're this big
and then and muscles would cramp up on
me too like not during the workout like
later on the day doing something
completely unrelated
and muscles would just just tighten up
muscles i didn't even know i had you
know
he said they're talking to somebody well
that's a good point
do i have muscle in my ear is this this
is
have i been working on my ears what's
going on be honest are my ears getting
big
ridiculous that was crazy and then
there's one video on there
um it's called plyometrics it's jump
training a lot of this action a lot of
jump
a lot of jump training action right a
lot of it's more athletic than i'm
making it look
it's i'm not it's not supposed to look
like an episode of glee that's what i'm
trying to tell you
it's not supposed to look like that just
look better
but doing that video and those of you
who have done it you gotta back me up on
this
uh there's four people on the video
showing you how to do it okay
one of the guys has only one leg
there's a one-legged guy doing jump
training
like he's got a really good prosthetic
leg but he's just going he's just like
and i can't keep up to him right i can't
tell a one-legged guy come on
[Laughter]
and i know what they're doing they're
trying to motivate you right but it
makes you feel horrible
they're like hey if he can do it that
means that you can do it but it just
makes you feel terrible when you can't
keep up
and every video they stick somebody in
there right there's like this
nine-year-old woman
doing pull-ups just like crazy
no that's not true grandma's gotta be
juicing that can't be real
come on i'm biting on that one
every video they stick somebody on there
look at this look at this one she just
gave birth three hours ago
three hours ago she was in labor and
she's doing stomach crunches if she
there's her baby doing it a three hour
old baby
baby's jacked
i'm tired
and here's the reason the real reason i
was i started to do this this p90x
if i'm being honest with you um i was
just
i was just trying to get my arms a
little bigger that was my plan if i
could just get my arms just a little bit
bigger
then my hands wouldn't look as
ridiculous on my body if i could just do
something
it's worse than i move them have you
noticed that just show you my hands i
was getting a big hand and i move them
around oh buddy we just ate
stop it
every time i shake somebody's hand i
tickle their armpit that's too much
[Laughter]
it was tough growing up with hands this
big i didn't have the same finite motor
skills other kids had with their stubby
little hands you know
couldn't do the things they could do
it's not as well as them you know so i
didn't like the things we did in school
you know except for finger painting i
love finger painting here we go
i just finished seven projects
and i'm out of paper and paint actually
about a paint as well you want to bring
some over here
and i can help you no problem what's
that
no i have arms i just don't need them
lift them with the legs at the back
oh man i still finger paint by the way
it's kind of a hobby of mine now he's
doing some
some finger painting last weekend there
i uh i painted the garage
[Laughter]
let that dry suit hand signs to the deaf
to
the sign language for the deaf until
they made me stop because i was making
the deaf people mad
or something stop it it's too loud
[Laughter]
that doesn't look right either hey look
how small my head is in proportion did
you notice that
tiny head
and just so you know i want you to laugh
i do um but it hurts my feelings too
just so you know
here's the number here's the numbers
though just so you know the difference
uh
so glove size uh 4xl okay
um hat size youth medium so that's
embarrassing
seriously mama goes up big and tall and
my hat's a baby gap
your selection's horrible by the way
those are beanies
and here's the truth of it when you hear
comedy like it's real stories true
stories these things really did happen
but little comedic twists on the end a
little bit sometimes right give a little
so real glove size 4xl absolutely true
um my real hat size is not actually
youth medium my real hat size is
actually
uh youth small
but i had to change it because people
weren't laughing because i guess they
thought well that's ridiculous it can't
be that small
just think about that for a second that
means my head is actually so small that
it's not even funny anymore that's what
that means
small hand
i had a lady come to after after a show
on time oh over here by the way here's
how you know your head is too small of
your hands you shouldn't be able to
touch both your ears with one hand at
the same time that's how you know
[Applause]
i love watching people try that's like
halfway on my face what's going on here
that means you're normal i believe
there's a guy to show a couple weeks ago
he's like you can do it if you open your
mouth
why would you want to i don't know i had
laid comfy after a show one time she was
offended i was doing jokes about the
size of my hands
the very jokes she just heard she was
offended and she said and i quote
sets a bad example for kids about making
fun of themselves
what do you even say to that you know i
was like um
maybe comedy's not for you it's not your
thing
it's my uh
it's my own fault though cause i uh i
married her
[Music]
the latest thing that happened i was
playing the uh the xbox 360s my son
there has to connect
right so it has a controller but you
also are the controller i don't know
what game this would be
dance like a canadian
anyway we were doing a nike plus for
connect it's like a home workout that
you do right with the connect
gives your own personal trainer right so
if you're doing a workout
video you can kind of cheat a little bit
right maybe not do the exercises well
enough
video doesn't know but with the personal
trainer they're like hey hey
get your knees up higher or whatever
right but north of them do they have to
know what your body looks like you've
got to stand in front of the connect
camera while it's mapping out your body
and i was watching it on the screen
as i was mapping on my body got to my
head and i'm not making this up
there's this little red little red
square around my head with this error
message
you know what the error message said
cannot detect head
xbox got jokes
i turned around my son was howling he
thought it was the funniest thing he'd
ever seen he's literally bent over
shaking he's laughing so hard
like what are you laughing at you look
just like me you freak
laughing at yourself that's what you're
doing
hang on i'm just going to grab a quick
sip of water that's a 2-liter bottle by
the way
[Applause]
i don't know uh you could tell my kids
are going to be freaks just like me
though
right when they were born massive hands
right right from the
we're in the hospital the birthing event
there right and first of all i don't do
well in hospitals to begin with you know
and i guess my wife was in a bit of
discomfort too
right so this was some serious no that's
what that's
what she said um
imagine she's being honest anyway she's
up on the delivery table there she's got
the
uh all ready to go there and she's got
the um
uh the thing on she's wearing the uh
gown right i was gonna say kilt i don't
even know what i was thinking
like there's some scottish hospitals
over here all right last give a great
picture for dr mcgregor
look at the size of his hands
quicker slap him before he slaps us off
[Laughter]
surprised he made it he did
and it was free
you guys did that kind of i see what
you're saying
get what you pay for buddy
[Music]
i don't know i don't like hospitals i
just i hate and there is a difference
though canadians and americans that is
one of the biggest differences i noticed
just our mentality when it comes to
hospitals and things like that uh in
canada
especially where i grew up you just you
go to the doctor all the time for every
little thing here you don't go to the
doctor
ever right there you just you're always
where i grew up we'd go to the doctor
for something to do sometimes
be a slow saturday you want to go to the
mall is the doctor's office what do you
feel like
get to the doctor's house and be like
okay okay leland what seems to be the
problem
well today's truth doctor i kind of feel
kind of um
bored that's what i'm here for
i don't know we uh we passed that
mentality onto our our kids
generations it's true my kids were like
so i was 16 year old
uh when he was three years old he was
really upset one day crying he was
really upset he was crying
and he said this to me this is exactly
what he said to me this is this is how
we think about doctors
he's like dad i've got an itchy bum can
you take me to the doctor
that's what he said he wanted to go to
the doctor for an itchy bum
so we went because i was bored
see what happens see what he does
and it was prescription drugs which is
what all western medicine does
sorry is that hurtful oh
i work with a pharmaceutical company
don't call us out on this
but it's a different mentality right it
really is like my i had a comedian
friend he had a son the same age and we
were talking about it one time
i was telling about what my son had said
and he was like if my son said that
my son was like dad my bum is itchy he'd
just look at him and say
drag it on the carpet like the dog does
okay i don't care
go do it not not the couch the carpet
get down
i've got decent care though i can't
complain i blew my knee out a couple
of a couple of years back i was playing
house i was playing some basketball i
was showing off to these kids hey look
what i can do and then
yeah i can cry like a baby everybody
gather around and watch
i completely severed the tendons lower
part of my kneecap just blew right off
like
so it was wasn't attached on the bottom
at all but it was still attached on the
top so it actually went up
it was like like it didn't make that
noise it wasn't a
cartoon injury here but i had to get i
had to get surgery right away and i
wasn't in vancouver where i lived i was
in calgary at the time so i went to the
hospital there
and they had to i guess they got to work
on it right away uh so
they're wheeled me in for for surgery
and i don't have been for surgery lately
uh but it's freezing cold in there like
i'm from
canada i know cold it was like meat lock
or cold
like i don't even know how they operate
i was getting worried they're wheeled me
and i was like hey
uh you guys know i'm alive right you're
not uh
i'm harvesting my organs or something
are you be honest what's going on
and then they said to me do you want to
be completely under or do you just want
to
just want to not feel the leg i was like
well
i want to be under i'm pretty sure why
would somebody want to be awake
well it's a control thing what kind of
control would you have you just be
heckling the whole time
yeah come on this is bush league
no wonder this is free
i wanted to be out i was like i want to
be out till rehab's done
i wanna right i wanna wake up six months
from now oh yeah that's good that's way
better
yeah thank you that was the worst part
was the ream
so what they did was they grabbed the
tendons pulled them up drilled some
holes
and reattached it i'm assuming i wasn't
awake
and what the what the doctor said he
said so acl mcl
surgeries you got to you got to be
moving that right away you don't want to
lose movement it's really tough to get
movement back in your knee
he said with this one it's right over
the top so if you bend
before uh it's completely healed
then you got to start all over again so
no bending no flexing for six weeks
right that's what he said and then i
went back back to vancouver and to get
follow visits from uh
uh from uh from orthodontics
orthodontics
turns out i had gingivitis too what
man was this a week
no the orthopedic surgeon there was like
well let's give it a bend and see what
happens
i was like no no buddy said not to and
he's like what does he know
i don't know but uh maybe credentials is
a really good thing we should be looking
at isn't it
i guess his theory was you just got to
see where you're at see the see how far
you've come so he just wanted to kind of
see
the progress right but he used to scare
me every single time i went in there he
would just want to see
a little bit more come on dude come on
just do a little bit more i just want to
do some yoga put your foot in the back
of your head let's
afraid he's going to stay like that or
something how am i going to defend
canadian healthcare to americans
no it's a stair leg it's for stairs
mainly it's really
really handy on the stairwork i'll tell
you
it also looks like you're going really
fast you're just walking normal
so i'm lying in the the hospital bed um
right after surgery i got a straight leg
cast on
okay and i'm not allowed to put any
weight on it but i kept having to get up
and go to the bathroom
right first of all i was cold i was
nervous
i have a small bladder i'm pretty sure
it's another medical issue
but i kept having to go so every time i
got up to go um
i kept using the iv pole kind of like a
crutch a little wheels in the bottom so
i kind of lean on that
kind of shuffle off to the to the
bathroom right um but every time i did
this because i wasn't supposed to be on
my own the nurse
kept coming to help me because i wasn't
supposed to cheat you know the door was
open she could see
and i went a lot i'm not gonna lie to
you
and she was getting really tired of this
i could see it in her eyes she started
to roll a little bit
so finally she just said to me listen
why don't you just use the bedpan
that's what it's there for just use the
bedpan but she's been saying the exact
same thing to my uh
my roommate right he wasn't this close
he was over he was
really short on beds in canada right jim
i said surgery stop hogging the covers
now i gotta pee again thanks no he was
over he was over
but he didn't want to use it either was
the same reason i didn't want to use it
so i thought
you know what i'm just going to tell her
so that she knows so i was like listen
the reason we don't want to use the
bedpan honestly
is that it's humiliating it's
embarrassing you know
you come and fill it up and then we know
she doesn't
[Laughter]
clearly didn't understand how to work
day thank you
[Laughter]
yeah you're right that's better you're
right i shouldn't have doubted you
you go
no but i said there it's it's
humiliating it's embarrassing as i said
that i turned to go to the bathroom
again
and this is an absolutely true story i
was wearing a hospital gown
which uh uh in hindsight
um it was wide open in fact
it's humiliating that's what it is
i've got dignity that's what i've got
that's you're looking at right now man
with dignity
[Applause]
[Music]
i tell i tell my wife of those stories
because it happened
and she just shakes her head she's like
you're such an idiot sometimes
which is true um i'm married been
married for uh for
22 years yeah
[Applause]
yeah she's all right i don't mind her
no major beefs
you see people look some people's faces
why would he say that
that was hurtful
you know i've done some good things in
those 22 years
a lot of love has changed though it has
you can't keep the puppy love forever
right it used to be i remember talking
my phone on the my wife on the phone in
the old days
uh it was a sappiest puppy lovey doggy
thing
did you like it was sickening it was so
sappy it was like right before shows i
was like i love you more
i think you love me because i just did i
did you are
the sponsor because if you were
listening you would know that i did it
make myself sick sometimes but it's
changed now it's grown it's matured
right i was talking my wife on the phone
before the show tonight and you just
tell us it's different now you know it's
like okay i should probably get going
yeah i love you oh remember i love you
more remember those days when you see
that
hello
this is pretty smart things for a small
brain guy though i'll give you some
advice fellas take this one
um i used to write little love notes to
my wife all the time
not love notes and then hand them to her
here's the love note i'd make tons of
them
hide them all over the house right so
she'd be opening a drawer or something
oh
you love it super romantic it was
awesome
smartest thing i ever did right because
i haven't done it in like i don't know
like 18 years and she's still finding
them you know
all right oh that goes romantic
hey is it me
for sure okay i thought they were gone
i'll take that
yeah i do some habits kind of driving
crazy though a little bit i talk in my
sleep
a little bit of a bit of a sleep talker
i also sleep my eyes open every once in
a while
yeah it can be a little bit well here's
where it gets really creepy sometimes i
combine the two
i should roll from bed and have a me
stare at you
mr jenkins wants more soup
i like cheese
[Laughter]
not a great joke in this corner i
realize that now i'm just
probably not the best story
all right am i american sorry sorry
story um
uh here's one here's another habit she
says i have and and
i mean it's probably partially true but
she says that i have road rage
and and to be maybe i do that's fine but
if i have road rage then my wife's got
what i call
broad mag i would say just from start to
finish just
slow down speed up blah blah blah
i'm happy to begin with two blocks in
i'm just gripping that wheel
get out of the way gotta drop off the
wife
it's a very small car it's a very small
true story would drive along this bridge
it was the middle of winter we uh we hit
this sheet of black ice and we started
spinning around out of control on this
bridge
and it's a high bridge you go off into
the river and you're gonna die okay
in the middle of the accident we didn't
even know the outcome yet we're in the
middle
of the accident and she's giving me the
gears about it hey i told you to slow
down what i'm trying to do get me killed
not initially but i'm starting to work
after it
now will you please let me finish
texting
[Applause]
[Music]
crazy i um and to be okay
so that story was pretty much verbatim
maybe not exactly but close
the only thing different is her when i
make her voice sound like that
she it's not quite like that she i don't
know how to describe this my wife
doesn't know how to yell
do you know anything like this when she
yells it sounds like she's pretending to
yell
but she knows the pitch has to go higher
but she can't bring the volume up at the
same time
it's the funniest thing when she gets
mad and starts yelling i'm getting sick
and tired of this song
what what are you are you mad you're mad
aren't you are you mad neighborhood dogs
are like
[Applause]
sorry it'll be like this i guess
actually that's a llama now that's obama
um i don't know why i did that either
i just heard that llama but here's the
thing i'll make her yell sometimes just
so i can hear it because it's funny to
me
you know it's it's like let me up to the
boys and tell that it's time to eat
uh actually i'm just gonna just gonna
start something over here
do you mind doing it
watch her walk to the bottom of the
banister boys
boys i said it's time
you better get down here right now
before i get really mad
hey honey i'll be on with the boys
there's dogs gathering at the front door
and a llama is that a llama it's weird
but here's the thing we've been married
for 22 years wonderful years i love her
very much
yeah but we've had sure you can if you
want
but here's the thing we have had some
fights over the years
we've had some arguments we've had some
screaming matches
i'm pretty sure and that's happened the
neighbors think i'm yelling at myself
huh
oh come on let me always say that i say
that
no i don't do what you say dude it's not
even true and it's true
you know what i'm sick of getting yelled
at
[Applause]
the neighbors like leland's yelling at
himself again
and where's our dog where did our dog go
is he over there
why does he keep doing that here's the
thing you guys i gotta i gotta get out
of here i gotta finish uh hanging these
plants in the back
um just barely started and we started
the show so i gotta finish my
work that's my work visa it's i'm a
horticulturist
um it's the only way i can get down here
no but i will leave you this i i do love
my wife very much i make a lot of jokes
about her
i do but i i love her i love her very
much um
uh but our wedding day uh worst day
of our entire life together horrible day
just from start to finish absolutely
everything that could possibly go wrong
went wrong
on that day and i found out recently i
guess that was my fault
um or certain expectations you ladies
have if you don't tell us we don't know
for example when a woman comes down the
aisle when a bride comes down the aisle
fellas you know there's a certain look
you're supposed to have in your face
when you first see her
did you know that sir no because they
don't tell us how do we know
right as far as i can figure out too
this is this is what a woman wants to
see when she comes down the aisle that's
what she wants to be waiting for at the
altar should look something like this
[Laughter]
laughs
something like that right you take that
right
it's a little cheesy you're probably
thinking it's a little but you take it
over this this is what my wife got this
is waiting for her at the altar it looks
something like this
[Laughter]
[Applause]
[Music]
um
[Laughter]
[Music]
you guys have been fantastic thank you
so much
you